The Muppets... Scotland Yard... jewel thieves...
lead to high adventure in London.
The Great Muppet Caper is a family, comedy, crime film directed by Jim Henson.
Kermit and Fozzie are newspaper reporters sent to London to interview Lady Holiday, a
wealthy fashion designer whose priceless diamond necklace is stolen.
Kermit meets and falls in love with her secretary, Miss Piggy.
The jewel thieves strike again, and this time frame Miss Piggy.
It's up to Kermit and Muppets to bring the real culprits to justice.
Kermit the Frog / Rowlf the Dog / Dr. Teeth /  Waldorf / Swedish
Chef / The Muppet Newsman, played by Jim Henson.
Miss Piggy / Fozzie Bear / Sam the Eagle / Animal  (voice), played by Frank Oz.
Gonzo / Beauregard / Zoot / Dr. Bunsen Honeydew /
Lobbuck Lou, played by Dave Goelz.
Floyd Pepper / Pops / Lew Zealand / Crazy Harry /
Louis Kazager, played by Jerry Nelson.
Scooter / Statler / Sweetums / Janice / Beaker / Bubba, played by Richard Hunt.
Rizzo the Rat / Lips (voice), played by Steve Whitmire.
The Great Muppet Caper is a 1981 musical heist comedy film directed by Jim Henson (in his
feature directorial debut) and the second theatrical film featuring the Muppets.
The film stars Muppet performers Henson, Frank Oz, Dave Goelz, Jerry Nelson, Richard Hunt, and Steve Whitmire, as well as Charles
Grodin and Diana Rigg, with special cameo appearances by John Cleese, Robert Morley, Peter Ustinov, and Jack Warden.
The film was produced by ITC Entertainment and The Jim Henson
Company and distributed by Universal Pictures.
In the plot, the Muppets are caught up in a jewel heist
while investigating a robbery in London.
The Great Muppet Caper was released by Universal Pictures and Associated Film Distribution on
26 June 1981 in the United States and on 30 July 1981 in the United Kingdom.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed
$31.2 million against a $14 million budget.
It is the only Muppets feature film directed by Henson.
Shot in the United Kingdom in 1980, the film was released
shortly after the final season of The Muppet Show.
The film explores themes of london, england, great
britain, england, puppetry, reporter.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.